jonprell.com Cincinnati, OH www.github.com/JTP709

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for JavaScript and four years of diverse professional experience in the field of Health and Safety as an EHS Professional. Looking to leverage my drive for continuous improvement into a new career as a Full-Stack Engineer.

- Programming, Database, and Markup Languages: Python, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, HTML5, CSS3
- Frameworks and Libraries: Flask, jQuery, Knockout.js, Bootstrap
- Additional Skills: Linux (Ubuntu distribution), AWS (Lightsail), Apache2 HTTP Server, Google APIs

Projects

Portfolio Site GitHub Link November 2017

- Professional portfolio site to provide prospective employers an opportunity to review my professional work.
- Deployed on a Python/Flask back-end and jQuery front-end.

Emergency Event Manager

GitHub Link

October 2017

- Real-time event mapping app to assist an Emergency Manager during a major disaster event.
- Built using Knockout's JavaScript library and MVVP framework, Google's JavaScript API, and FourSquare's API.

Safety Management System

GitHub Link

August 2017

- Compliance system to help small businesses easily manage their recordkeeping within regulatory guidelines.
- Deployed using Python with PostgreSQL back-end architecture, 3rd party authentication, and Bootstrap front-end UI.

Work Experience

Amazon.com

September 2015 – October 2017

Safety Specialist

Hebron, KY

- Collaborated with operations team across 7 departments to reduce night shift injuries by 50% through training, concise reporting methodologies, and proactive engagement of the 1,500+ associates.
- Deployed StrongArm Tech's FUSE Platform to achieve a 33% reduction in injuries in the most high-risk departments and 0 muscle strain or ergonomic-related injuries for the associates participating in the program.
- Coordinated with Vaculux and Amazon Engineering to pilot a new material handling solution that generated a 10% increase in productivity with zero injuries on two test stations.

Marathon Petroleum Company

Health, Environmental, Safety and Security Co-Op

August 2014 - August 2015

Detroit, MI and Cincinnati, OH

- Authored site-specific emergency response procedures, facilitated emergency management training across 4 shifts, and coordinated with external emergency response agencies including the Cincinnati Fire and Police Departments.
- Collected noise dosimetry sampling data and produced a noise isopleth for the 250-acre MFD Refinery.

Barnes Aerospace

September 2013 – May 2014

Environmental Health and Safety Co-Op

West Chester, OH

- Participated in 2 Kaizen events that reduced employee exposure to air contaminants by 66% while reducing waste.
- Inventoried 200+ individual machine items then rebuilt the work order system to reduce redundant work orders by 33% while improving regulatory compliance documentation processes.

Kentucky Army National Guard

February 2006 – February 2008

Louisville, KY

- Produced detailed analytical datasets from metadata intelligence for the 20th Special Forces Group (Airborne).
- Partnered with NCO Leadership in field support tasks during high-risk airborne operations with 0 injuries.

Education and Certification

Signals Intelligence Analyst

Udacity

Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree

www.udacity.com

November 2017

Eastern Kentucky University

Richmond, KY

August 2015

Bachelor of Science in Homeland Security and Criminal Justice

Master of Science in Safety, Security, Emergency Management

May 2012